

BIMALESH SAHOO

User Experience Designer

INFO

Address:

Ingolstadt, Germany

Skype:

bimalesh.sahoo

Email:

sahoo.bimalesh@gmail.com

Portfolio:

https://sahoobimalesh.in

Behance:

behance.net/bimaleshsahoo

SKILLS

UX Research, Wireframing
UI Design, Prototyping, User
Personas, Interaction Design
Team Management,
Analytics, iOS Application
Development, Responsive
Web Design, Augmented
Reality

TOOLS

Sketch

Adobe XD

Axure RP

Xcode

Photoshop

Illustrator

Figma

PROFILE

Pursuing M.Sc. in User Experience Design at Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. A Developer converted into a Creative Designer with 4.5 years of professional experience working in the field of User Experience Designing. Original and clever with the ability to work with design and development teams. Better understanding of requirements, business goals, design guidelines and converting prepared solutions into innovative wireframes by creating work flows and interactive designs.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dassault Systèmes, User Experience Designer

Pune

Oct 2019 - Nov 2020

- Involved in define and design of Document Management Application on the 3DEXPERIENCE Platform.
- Completed user research to identify opportunities for improving web presence.
- Facilitated clients' product vision by researching, conceiving, sketching, prototyping.
- Designed UI elements and tools such as navigation menus, search boxes, tabs and widgets for digital components.

Wipro Limited, User Experience Designer

Pune

July 2016 - Oct 2019

- Designed and built advanced applications for the iPhone, iPads, Web platform.
- Collaboration with functional teams to define, design and ship new features.
- Have got a great exposure with clients and customers by working with them.
- Worked in a fast paced, agile and in an ownership and results oriented culture.
- Close interaction with the development teams to get the best out of designs.
- Ability to handle and lead a team ensuring deliverables within stipulated time.

EDUCATION

M.Sc in User Experience Design

Nov 2020 - present

Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt

Ingolstadt, Germany

B.Tech in Electronics & Communication

Gangtok, India

June 2012 - June 2016

Sikkim Manipal Institute of Technology